Tiffany Harris

Email: <u>tiffanyaharris711@gmail.com</u> | Phone: 704-352-4094 | Address: 733 Sid Rich Dr, Irving, TX 75039 LinkedIn: <u>https://linkedin.com/in/tiffany-harris-analyst</u> | GitHub: <u>https://github.com/tiffanyharris711</u>

CAREER SUMMARY

Data reporting analyst with over 17 years' data mining experience in business analytics and cross-organization collaboration seeking BI Engineer position. Specializing in data-driven process improvement from concept to launch. Direct communication and analytical insights to regularly support key business decision making. Strong business acumen, data manipulation and mathematical skills.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python | GitHub | Power BI | DAX | Tableau | SQL Queries | Power Apps | SharePoint | PostgreSQL | Machine Learning | Scikit Learn | MongoDB | Excel | Pivot Tables | Power Query | Relational Databases | MS Access | HTML | CSS | Flask | JavaScript | Visual Basic for Applications (VBA) | RESTful API | EDI | ETL Processing

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Business Administration - Georgia State University, J. Mack Robinson College of Business Certificate in Data Science and Analytics - Southern Methodist University Certificate in Data Analysis and Visualization with Excel - New Horizons Computer Learning Center Certificate in Basic Structured Query Language (SQL) - New Horizons Computer Learning Center

PROJECTS

NFL Fantasy Football Points Analysis | https://github.com/tiffanyharris711/pandasy-football | Apr 2021 Leveraged data manipulation to merge flat files with RESTful API requests to design the ideal fantasy team. Showcased relationships using Matplotlib visualizations.

Skills used: ETL | REST API | Python | Pandas | Matplotlib

Interactive Pokémon Go Dashboard | https://github.com/tiffanyharris711/gotta-cache-em-all | May 2021 Performed ETL in Python programming collecting 900 Pokémon Go profiles from RESTful API requests converting JSON data with Pandas. Data manipulated using SQLite database.

Skills used: ETL | API | Python | Pandas | SQLite | Flask | CSS | HTML | Bootstrap | JavaScript | D3.js | Anime

Analyzing Stock Prices Against Online Mentions | https://github.com/tiffanyharris711/callstreet-bets | June 2021 Manipulated data from Reddit's Wallstreet Bets user posts in Pandas counting the number of mentions per stock ticker. Created HTML embedded data visualization using Tableau. Predicted future stock price changes using Scikit Learn machine learning library in Python.

Skills used: ETL | Python | Pandas | Sci-Kit Learn | Machine Learning | Flask | Tableau | HTML | JavaScript

WORK EXPERIENCE

Gourmet Foods International - Atlanta, GA

Jan 2013 - Present

Business Intelligence Manager, Data Modeling | Jan 2020 – Present

- Pioneered data visualization strategy and engineered data models from 55M record dataset.
- Developed relational database with user entry forms reducing manual processing by 30+ hours weekly.
- Integrated online payment system increasing automatic customer payments by 142%.
- Served as project manager to transition on premise server to cloud environment for EDI platform for entire project lifecycle—while managing 1.75 million EDI transactions.
- Translated technical requirements for EDI testing while collaborating with 100+ internal stakeholders, 40+ customers, and 30+ suppliers for EDI implementations.

E-Commerce Coordinator, EDI Programming | Jan 2013 – Jan 2020

- Audited \$400 million in EDI transactions, online customer portal and mobile ordering app.
- Constructed programming for 250+ EDI projects while auditing daily error logs and monitoring transmissions.

Airgas Dry Ice - Lawrenceville, GA

Jan 2011 – Dec 2012

Manager of Business Support | Jan 2012 – Dec 2012

- Led 7-member cross-functional team (sales analyst, customer service, and contract management).
- Audited 50+ national warehouse locations ensuring data quality and compliance with company operating procedures.
- Implemented training for 30 account sales managers, including on-site and interactive web learning.
- Forecasted business metrics for \$200 million annual budget and produced quantitative insights for sales presentations.

Business Analyst | Jan 2011 – Jan 2012

- Maintained cost models for gross margin profitability and generated ad-hoc reporting for executive teams.
- Designed custom relational databases to easily track KPIs and monitor organization performance.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Previous positions at **Gourmet Foods International** in Atlanta, GA include **Retail Sales Analyst Manager**, **Retail Sales Analyst**, **Purchasing Agent**, **Foodservice Sales Analyst**, **Customer Service Representative**, **Receptionist**.